<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<document>
	<properties>
		<title>Changes History</title>
		<author email="matteo.merli@gmail.com">Matteo Merli</author>
	</properties>
	<body>

		<release version="3.0-ALPHA5-SNAPSHOT" date="in SVN">

			<action dev="rbieniek" type="update">
				Restructured project for multi-module project.
			</action>

			<action dev="rbieniek" type="add">
				Added OSGi bundle skeleton.
			</action>

			<action dev="rbieniek" type="add">
				Added support for XML based comfiguration files.
			</action>

			<action dev="rbieniek" type="update">
				Configuration has been changed from property-file to XML
				config file. The configuration has been changed to allow
				multiple filters per type and each filter may take its
				configuration information from a central configuration
				file.
			</action>

			<action dev="rbieniek" type="update">
				Changed logging framework from log4j to slf4j (Simple
				Logging Facade for Java). This change streamlines the
				logging framework with the underlying mina logging
				approach. This changes also allows an easier integration
				into containers which provide their own logging
				mechanisms (like OSGi).
			</action>

			<action dev="rbieniek" type="add">
				Added a concept of filters being applied to the upstream
				(remote server) connection and the downstream client
				connection. This allows for example IP addess based
				filters which might constrain access to either the
				streaming proxy, to remote streaming servers or both.
			</action>

			<action dev="rbieniek" type="add">
				Made installed filters manageable through JMX. An
				individual filter can be suspended or resumed via JMX
				and may provide addtional management capabilites by
				exposing an linked MBean.
			</action>

			<action dev="rbieniek" type="add">
				All RTSP filters are now managed through a central
				filter registry. This will allow the dynamic
				reconfiguration of the applied filter chain per new
				session.
			</action>

			<action dev="rbieniek" type="update">
				Made URL rewriting working again. This filter is
				actually applied to both the client and the server
				connection because it needs to modify both request and
				response. The response filter currently honours the
				Content-base header, the RTP-Info header is not
				processed yet.
			</action>

		</release>

		<release version="3.0-ALPHA4" date="not released" />

		<release version="3.0-ALPHA3" date="not released">
			<action dev="merlimat" type="add">
				Added support for RDT transport and RealVideo streams.
			</action>
			<action dev="merlimat" type="change">
				Refactored the configuration subsystem.
			</action>
			<action dev="merlimat" type="add">
				Added JMX complaint remote management capabilities.
			</action>
			<action dev="merlimat" type="add">
				Added accounting filter to log accesses to the proxy
				service.
			</action>
		</release>

		<release version="3.0-ALPHA2" date="2005-12-08">
			<action dev="merlimat" type="add">
				Added preliminary implementation of the IP address and
				host name filter.
			</action>
			<action dev="merlimat" type="fix">
				Fixed Windows startup script.
			</action>
			<action dev="merlimat" type="update">
				Using only a UDP port pair for all RTP/RTCP packet
				handling and sending for all the connected clients.
			</action>
			<action dev="merlimat" type="fix">
				Properly clear session data when a session is closed.
			</action>
			<action dev="merlimat" type="fix">
				Fixed several NullPointerException.
			</action>
			<action dev="merlimat" type="update">
				Faster parsing of RTSP messages.
			</action>
			<action dev="merlimat" type="add">
				Handling proper shutdown of the service.
			</action>
		</release>

		<release version="3.0-ALPHA1" date="2005-10-24">
			<action dev="merlimat" type="add">
				Completely rewritten the proxy from scratch in Java
			</action>
		</release>

		<release version="2.4.1" date="2005-02-28">
			<action dev="merlimat" type="fix">
				Fixed a compilation bug.
			</action>
		</release>

		<release version="2.4" date="2005-02-09">
			<action type="fix" dev="merlimat">
				In this release there are many important bug fixes that
				make the proxy works with major RTSP streaming servers
				and video players.
			</action>
			<action type="update" dev="merlimat">
				The proxy was ported to MacOsX and now it can be
				compiled using a various Gcc versions (2.95, 3.1, 3.3,
				3.4).
			</action>
		</release>
	</body>
</document>

