<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>

<document>
	<!-- $Id$
	     $URL$
	-->

	<properties>
		<author email="matteo.merli@gmail.com">Matteo Merli</author>
		<title>Reverse Proxy</title>
	</properties>

	<body>
		<section name="Reverse Proxy">
			<p>A reverse proxy works very similarly as the normal proxy 
			operating mode, but with a few important differences.
			</p>
			<p>First, instead of being tightly coupled with clients, the
			reverse proxy it's coupled with servers and it's transparent
			to clients.
			</p>
			<p>The primary purpose of a reverse proxy is to serve as 
			a "<i>frontend</i>" for one or more RTSP servers. The proxy will
			act as a public façade for the server.
			</p>
			<div align="center">
				<img src="images/reverseProxy.png" alt="Reverse proxy schema" />
			</div>

			<subsection name="Benefits">
				<p>A real world example would the case of a IP web-cam with
				RTSP capabilities. Generally these IP cams are running an
				embedded RTSP server wich can safely serve the stream to
				no more than very few simultaneous clients.
				</p>
				<p>The media server can be in an internal network segment and
				being not accessible from public networks.
				</p>
			</subsection>

			<subsection name="Configuration">
				<p>Configuring the RTSP-Proxy to act as a reverse proxy
				it's simply a matter of using the 
				<a href="rewriteFilter.html">Rewrite Filter</a> and
				setup a few url rewriting rules.
				</p>
				<p>As in the above figure example, the rewrite rule would be:
				</p>
				<source>&lt;rules&gt;
    &lt;mapping&gt;
        &lt;from&gt;rtsp://domain.com:554/path&lt;/from&gt;
        &lt;to&gt;rtsp://10.0.0.2:1554/newPath&lt;/to&gt;
    &lt;/mapping&gt;
&lt;/rules&gt;</source>
			<p>The rewriting filter will take care of rewriting the media url in
			RTSP requests and responses so that nor the client or the server
			will note something strange.
			</p>
			<p>The client does not need to be <i>proxy-aware</i>, in the sense 
			that it will simply connect to the host specified in the url of 
			the media resource, thinking it is talking with a regular RTSP server.
			</p>
			</subsection>
                </section>
        </body>
</document>


